(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.1",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
告知：百鬼あやめ 新衣装3D 天女繚華
Announcement: Nakiri Ayame New Outfit 3D - Tennyo Ryouka
7周年記念ライブ 2025.9.3 20:00
7th Anniversary Memorial Live - Sept 3, 2025, 20:00
百鬼あやめ
Nakiri Ayame
兎田ぺこら / Azki
Usada Pekora / Azki
大神ミオ / 白上フブキ
Ookami Mio / Shirakami Fubuki
さくらみこ / 雪花ラミィ
Sakura Miko / Yukihana Lamy
フワワ・アビスガード / モココ・アビスガード
Fuwawa Abyssgard / Mococo Abyssgard
天音かなた / 宝鐘マリン
Amane Kanata / Houshou Marine
ゆらゆらり
Swaying gently
はらはらり
Fluttering down
色とりどり
In various colors
乱れ咲き
Blooming profusely
花の街
City of flowers
想い出し
Recalling
この空から
From this sky
百花繚乱
作詞・作曲：棚田りら
Hyakka Ryouran
Lyrics/Composition: Tanada Rira
そんな出来事から
From such events
やってきたこの場所は
This place I've come to
遥か遠くにあった
Which was far away
煌びやかな舞台
A glittering stage
ハッとするほど
So much that it takes my breath away
鮮やかな世界が
A vivid world
あるんだと知って
I came to know it exists
あなたの無理難題に
To your impossible demands
応えてくその度に
Every time I respond
あっと言わせるような
In a way that leaves you speechless
奇想天外な
Extraordinary
答え合わせで
By checking the answers
辿り着いたその先に
Beyond where I arrived
新しい景色が
A new scenery
待っているんだ
Is waiting
摩訶不思議なミステリー
A mysterious mystery
次から次へと
One after another
起こるたび
Every time it happens
巧妙なからくりも
Even the clever tricks
暴いてみせましょう
I shall uncover them all
どんな難題でも
No matter how difficult the challenge
種や仕掛けはあるんだ
There's a trick behind it
副作用は気にしない
I don't care about side effects
必ずや導き出すから
Because I will surely find the way
あぁこの場所で触れた 人の哀しみや喜びがある
Ah, in this place I felt the sorrows and joys of people.
そのひとつひとつが 心を震わせる
Each and every one of them makes my heart tremble.
ハッとしちゃうほど 鮮やかな世界が ここにあるんだ
A world so vivid that it takes my breath away is right here.
あなたの無理難題に 応えていく毎日に
To the days spent responding to your impossible demands.
アッと言わせるような 奇想天外な答え合わせ
An unexpected answer that will make everyone say "Wow".
辿り着いたその先に 新しい私が待っているんだ
At the end of that journey, a new me is waiting.
あの頃は 想像もしていない未来が咲き始めている
A future that I couldn't even imagine back then is beginning to bloom.
こんな日々も 悪くはないかな
Maybe days like these aren't so bad.
ゆらゆらり ひらひらり
Swaying and fluttering...
離れては 寄り添って
Moving apart and then drawing close.
そよぐ風に身を任せ 幽夜に舞う
Entrusting myself to the gentle breeze, dancing in the moonlit night.
百花繚乱
Hyakka Ryouran
はい！ということで、今日は皆さん来てくれてありがとう！
Yes! So, thank you all for coming today!
みんな見てる？見てますかー？
Is everyone watching? Are you watching?
ということで見て！今日はこの新衣装なんですよ！
So, look! Today, I'm wearing this new outfit!
みんな気づいたよね？気づいたよね？さすがに。
Everyone noticed, right? You noticed, right? Surely.
はーい。ということで見てください、この煌びやかな和風の新衣装でーす！やったー！
Yes. So please take a look, it's a glittering Japanese-style new outfit! Yay!
ということでですね、これは今回、天女衣装となっております。
So, this time, it's called the "Tennyo" (Celestial Maiden) outfit.
傘も合わせて見てください。傘、ちょっと見えるかな？これ見て。
Please look at the umbrella too. Can you see it? Look at this.
余のね、ちょっと衣装と同じ柄で今回新しく作っていただきました！いぇーい！ありがとうございます。
It's made with the same pattern as my outfit this time! Yay! Thank you very much.
はい。ということでこの傘以外にもですね、
Yes. So, besides this umbrella,
ちょっとこの後、新しいアイテムもちょっと出てくるのでそちらは要チェックです！
some new items will appear later, so be sure to check those out!
というわけで、一曲目は「百花繚乱」を歌って踊らせていただきました！
Anyway, for the first song, I sang and danced to "Hyakka Ryouran"!
まだね、ちょっと花の蕾を使って、ちょっと新衣装にチェンジさせていただいたんですけど、どうでした？
I changed into the new outfit using flower buds, but how was it?
どうだったどうだった？おほほ。はい、ありがとうございます。可愛いですよねー。はい。
How was it? Ohoho. Yes, thank you. It's cute, isn't it? Yes.
ということで、今回のライブタイトルが「天女繚華」ということで、
So, the title of this live concert is "Tennyo Ryouka"...
この新衣装チェンジとか、これからのゲストの登場とかで、ちょっとねお花を多く使っているので、
...and with this new outfit change and the guests appearing later, we're using a lot of flowers.
花が咲き乱れるという意味を込めて今回この「天女繚華」というライブ名にさせていただきました。
With the meaning of flowers blooming in profusion, I named this live "Tennyo Ryouka".
見てちょっと。ちょっとね、後ろにもちらっとお花が見えたり、
Look a bit. You can see flowers peeking out from behind,
余の衣装にもちょっとお花があったり、なんだりしているんですけれども。
and there are some flowers on my outfit too.
はい。ということで、この衣装に合わせて今回もステージ新しく作っていただきました！やったー！
Yes. So, for this outfit, we had a new stage created again! Yay!
え、めっちゃ綺麗じゃない？見て！この桜と、
Eh, isn't it so beautiful? Look! These cherry blossoms and...
でっかい月！この、でーっかい月とね、両端にこっちにもありますけど桜。
...this huge moon! This huge moon and the cherry blossoms on both ends.
いや、めちゃめちゃ綺麗でしょ？すごいでしょこれ。もうめっちゃ考えました。
No, it's incredibly beautiful, right? It's amazing, isn't it? I thought about it a lot.
もう、めちゃくちゃねちょっと運営さんたちと一緒に、お話し合いをしたりとかして、ご実現していただきました。
I had many discussions with the staff to make this happen.
本当にありがとうございます。
Thank you so much.
ということで、この床にもね、ちょっとお分かりになります？気づきました？
So, on this floor too, can you tell? Did you notice?
ちょっとね、お花もこの散りばめられていたり、余の足元にもこの梅なのかな？
Some flowers are scattered around, and under my feet, are these plum blossoms?
このお花をこうね、ライトみたいな感じで照らしていただいたり、
These flowers are lit up like lights.
ちょっとね、細かくめっちゃ作ってもらってます。ありがとうございます。
It's been very finely crafted. Thank you.
なんで、それも含めてちょっとめちゃめちゃ見ていただきたいなと思っております。
So, I hope you'll take a good look at all of that too.
まあこのね、まあちょっと気になってますよね？この衣装。
Well, you're curious about this outfit, aren't you?
ちょっとみんなで近くで見てもらおうかな？
Should I let everyone see it up close?
じゃあちょっと、上からいいですかカメラさん？あ、ありがとうございます。
Then, camera operator, could you show me from above? Ah, thank you.
あ、このね、気づきました？このもう髪型からもちょっといつもと違うんですよ。ちょっとお団子。
Ah, did you notice? Even the hairstyle is different. A bit of a bun.
まあ、いつものちょっと3D衣装の雰囲気も残しつつ、残しつつね、ちょっと新しい髪型にさせていただきました。
While keeping the feel of my usual 3D outfit, I've gone with a new hairstyle.
...のね、梅っぽい花っぽい感じも入れていただきつつ...
...while also including this plum-like, flower-like feel...
...この見て！
...look at this!
見てください。あ、この振袖にもちゃんと付いてます、このお花。
Please take a look. Ah, these flowers are also properly included on these long sleeves.
綺麗でしょ。見て、綺麗でしょ。
They're beautiful, right? Look, they're beautiful, right?
よ、かわよでしょ。いいでしょ。
They're cute, right? They're nice, right?
はい、ということでこの足元にもちょっと注目していただきたいんですけど、見て！
Alright, I'd also like you to pay a bit of attention to my feet, look!
この草履も新しくなりました。可愛いよね。
These zori sandals have also been updated. They're cute, aren't they?
個性的よね。ちょっと袖の色と合わせて、
They're unique, right? Matching the colors of my sleeves slightly,
こっちはね白で、
this one is white,
こっちはちょっと茶色っぽい感じになってます。
and this one has a brownish feel to it.
そしてね、この衣装すごいところがね、どんだけ踊ってもですよ。
And, the amazing thing about this outfit is, no matter how much I dance.
足元見てください。めっちゃ伸びるんですこれ。
Please look at my feet. These stretch a lot.
凄いでしょ。これ。凄くないこれ。
Amazing, right? This. Isn't this amazing?
どんだけやってもめっちゃ伸びるからね。
Because they stretch a lot no matter what you do.
ということで、はい、小ネタでした。
So, yes, that was a little trivia.
はい。じゃあちょっと、まあこの新しい衣装にもなりましたし、
Alright. Well then, since I have this new outfit now,
新しいステージにもなったということで、
and we're also on a new stage,
じゃあちょっと、ちょっと一枚でもね、ちょっとお写真撮りますか、お写真。
well, shall we take a few photos? Photos.
このせっかくですし、この桜のさん、めっちゃ咲いてるところあるから、
Since we're here, there's a spot where the cherry blossoms are in full bloom,
ここでちょっとちょっと撮ろ、撮ろ。じゃあちょっとカメラさん来てください。
so let's take some photos here. Camera operator, please come over.
こっちこっちこっち。
This way, this way, this way.
あ、めっちゃ、めっちゃ映える。見て！
Oh, it looks really, really great on camera. Look!
凄いでしょ、これ。めっちゃ綺麗だよね。
Amazing, right? It's so beautiful.
このね、桜の色とかも。めっちゃ決めました。めっちゃ。
The color of the cherry blossoms and everything. I really went for it. Totally.
もうでもね、このライブ中にもめちゃめちゃ変わったりするのね。
But you know, it changes quite a lot during the live performance.
ライティングとかも変わったり、雰囲気もまた変わるので、
The lighting changes, the atmosphere changes as well,
それも含めて見てほしいんですけど。
so I'd like you to see all of that too.
ま、ちょっとそれを含めてここで、お写真なんか撮っちゃおうかな。
Well, with that in mind, I think I'll take some photos here.
みんな、みんなスクショいっぱい撮ってくださいね、
Everyone, please take lots of screenshots,
みんなハッシュタグ付けて。たくさんポストしてね。
using the hashtag. Post them a lot.
撮ってる撮れてる？いい感じ？
Are you taking them? Did you get them? How is it?
いい感じか？じゃあちょっと、傘なしバージョンもちょっとやってみますか。
Is it good? Well then, shall we try a version without the umbrella too?
どう？傘なし。傘なしもちょっと撮れるかしら。
How is it? Without the umbrella. I wonder if you can get some photos without it too.
あ、いいんじゃないいいんじゃない？あ、撮れてる？
Ah, isn't it good? It's good, right? Oh, did you get it?
お、撮れてますか。おお、めっちゃいい角度じゃん。
Oh, did you get it? Oh, that's a really great angle.
う、いい、いい、いい、いい。
Ooh, good, good, good, good.
はい。じゃあということで、ま、お写真はね、これくらいにさせていただきまして。
Alright. So, I think that's enough for the photos.
え、続きはね、ちょっと細かい衣装やら、ま、ちょっとスクショタイムはメイン念でね。
Next, I'll go over the details of the outfit, and for screenshot time, mainly...
ちょっと余剰のあと、思うんで。そのあともね、ミニライブとかもありますので、
later on. After that, there's also a mini-live,
そちらもぜひぜひ、え、チェックしていただければなと思います。
so I'd love for you to check that out as well.
そして、え、本日のハッシュタグはこちら。
And, here is today's hashtag.
え、ハッシュタグ「#百鬼あやめ7周年新衣装3D」で。
It's #NakiriAyame7thAnniversaryNewOutfit3D.
ちょっとね、長いんですけど、長いんですけど、
It's a bit long, it's long, but...
このたくさん綺麗なこのステージと、よの綺麗な衣装を、
...with this beautiful stage and my beautiful outfit,
たくさんたくさんスクショして、え、一緒にポストしてください！
...please take lots of screenshots and post them!
はい。ということで今回は、え、7周年を兼ねた。
Alright. So this time, it's also for the 7th anniversary.
え、7周年！？っていうことは、今7年やってるんですか！？っていう感じなんですけど。
7th anniversary!? Which means I've been doing this for 7 years!? That's how it feels.
え、今回はその7周年と、え、新衣装お披露目を兼ねたライブとなっております。
This live is for both the 7th anniversary and the new outfit reveal.
これからね、ゲストもたくさん呼んでいますので、楽しみにしていてください。
I've invited many guests from here on, so please look forward to it.
なんと、なんと！最後には、特大サプライズもあるので、
And, and! There's a huge surprise at the end,
え、絶対に最後まで見逃さないでね！
so definitely don't miss out until the very end!
チャンネルはそのままだよ！頼むね！
Don't change the channel! I'm counting on you!
夢の中でも 花が散ってる
Flowers are scattering even in my dreams
ひらひら舞う 暗闇に浮かぶ桜
Cherry blossoms floating in the darkness, dancing flutteringly
水面に落ちたら 君は
When you fall onto the water's surface, will you...
もう一度咲くのかな
...bloom once more, I wonder?
ひらひら ひらら
Hirahira Hirara
桜月夜に宿る
Dwelling in the cherry blossom moonlit night
いたずらな風 匂いだけ残して
A mischievous wind, leaving only a scent behind
騒ぎ出した...
Began to stir...
…騒ぎ出した
...began to stir.
記憶浮かび
Memories float up,
沈んでいく
and sink away.
思い出の破片 剥がれても
Even if pieces of memories peel away,
光る鱗で隠すの
I'll hide them with shining scales.
まばゆいほどに
To a dazzling degree,
美しい
how beautiful.
ひらひらひらら ひらひらひらら
Hira hira hirara, hira hira hirara,
瞼の裏 暗闇に浮かぶ桜
cherry blossoms floating in the darkness behind my eyelids.
水面に落ちたら
Once they fall onto the water's surface,
君は もう一度咲くのかな
I wonder if you'll bloom once more.
サヨナラしたら 会えないのでしょうが
If we say goodbye, we probably won't meet again, but...
言えないままの気持ちだけが
only these feelings I can't express...
花びら浮かんだ
floating like petals,
桜の橋になれ
become a bridge of cherry blossoms.
当たり前の景色が
The everyday scenery
ひらひらと舞い
dances flutteringly
音もなく消えていく
and vanishes without a sound.
細い雨に
In the light rain,
濡れた想い出が 霞んでいく
the drenched memories grow hazy.
他の誰かに 向けた笑顔見て
Seeing the smile you direct at someone else,
忘れた日は 蘇る
the forgotten days come back to life,
色のない夜を
staining the colorless night
染めていく
as it passes.
君と出会った 去年の春と
Just like that spring last year when I met you,
同じ場所で 同じ景色見つめてた
I gazed at the same scenery in the same place.
咲き誇るほどに 痛む
The more they bloom in full glory, the more it hurts,
君がいない桜
the cherry blossoms without you.
生まれ変わって また咲くのでしょうが
They'll probably be reborn and bloom again, but...
戻れない場所と知りながら
knowing it's a place I can never return to,
散りゆく花びら
taking the scattering petals
手のひらにのせて
and placing them in my palm.
花明かりに
Enticed by the cherry blossom light,
誘われて 胸の中に降り積もる
they pile up inside my chest.
光と影 舞い散る
Light and shadow dancing and scattering,
吹雪の思い出だけ
only the memories of that blizzard
白く染めていく
stain everything white.
ひらひらひらら ひらひらひらら
Hira hira hirara, hira hira hirara,
瞼の裏 暗闇に浮かぶ桜
cherry blossoms floating in the darkness behind my eyelids.
水面に落ちたら
Once they fall onto the water's surface,
君は もう一度咲くのかな
I wonder if you'll bloom once more.
サヨナラしたら 会えないのでしょうが
If we say goodbye, we probably won't meet again, but...
言えないままの気持ちだけが
even if only these feelings I can't express...
花びらに変わっても
change into petals...
君と出会った 去年の春と
Just like that spring last year when I met you,
同じ場所で 同じ景色見つめてた
I gazed at the same scenery in the same place.
咲き誇るほどに 痛む
The more they bloom in full glory, the more it hurts,
君がいない桜
the cherry blossoms without you.
夢の中でも 花が散っていく
Even in my dreams, the blossoms are scattering.
暗闇に浮かんだ桜が
The cherry blossoms floating in the darkness,
水面に落ちたら
once they fall onto the water's surface,
また会えるのかな
I wonder if we can meet again.
極楽浄土
Gokuraku Jodo
月明かり昇る刻
When the moonlight rises
灯る赤提灯
Red lanterns light up
祭囃子の合図
The signal of the festival music
ふわり蝶が誘い出す
A butterfly lightly lures you out
ちょいと覗いて見てごらん
Take a little peek and see
迷い込めば抜け出せない
Once you wander in, you can't get out
楽しいことがしたいなら
If you want to do something fun
おいでませ極楽浄土
Welcome to the Paradise Pure Land
歌えや歌え心のままに
Sing, oh sing, just as your heart desires
アナタの声をさあ聞かせて
Come on, let me hear your voice
踊れや踊れ時を忘れ
Dance, oh dance, forgetting time
今宵共にあー狂い咲き
Tonight, together, ah, let's bloom crazily
美しく咲く花も
Even the flowers that bloom beautifully
いつか散りゆくもの
Will eventually scatter and fade away
それならこの一夜を
If that's the case, this one night
もっと熱く愛したい
I want to love more passionately
ちょいと「いいこと」いたしましょう
Let's do something "good"
これは夢か幻か
Is this a dream or an illusion?
嘘も真も無い世界
A world where there's neither lie nor truth
ゆきましょう極楽浄土
Let's go to the Paradise Pure Land
歌えや歌え心のままに
Sing, oh sing, just as your heart desires
乱れる髪も気にせずに
Without even worrying about your disheveled hair
踊れや踊れ時を忘れ
Dance, oh dance, forgetting time
今宵共にあー狂い咲き
Tonight, together, ah, let's bloom crazily
ちょいと「いいこと」いたしましょう
Let's do something "good"
嘘も真も無い世界
A world where there's neither lie nor truth
ゆきましょう極楽浄土
Let's go to the Paradise Pure Land
歌えや歌え心のままに
Sing, oh sing, just as your heart desires
アナタの声をさあ聞かせて
Come on, let me hear your voice
踊れや踊れ時を忘れ
Dance, oh dance, forgetting time
今宵共にあー狂い咲き
Tonight, together, ah, let's bloom crazily
今宵アナタと狂い咲き
Tonight, with you, let's bloom crazily
許婚っきゅん
Kekkon Tsukkyun
どいつもこいつもなんだかやっぱノー天気
Everyone and their brother is just so carefree after all
気になるアンタの悩みもきっとあるでしょ
You must have some worries on your mind too, right?
雑多で半端な憂鬱も群れおなじ
All those messy, half-baked blues are just like the crowd
アンタの頭の中はグチャグチャさ
Your head is just a total mess
ドンマイ弊害意気地ない魔法的意識
Don't mind, the drawbacks, the spineless magical consciousness
いけないいけない事柄なんて無いから
Because there's no such thing as "bad" or "forbidden" things
イーアルサンスーじゃんけんぽんでさあゆき
One, two, three, rock-paper-scissors, let's go!
ウーリュウチーパクーで天に召されてく
Five, six, seven, eight, nine, being summoned to heaven
キミは
You are
もうハイスピードだありゃまこりゃまお待ちかね
Already at high speed, oh my, oh dear, just as you've been waiting for
ハチャでメチャなドラマ
A wild and crazy drama
派手にドラが鳴るよ
The gong will ring out loudly
いーいの？　ズキュン　I love you　なのな
Is it okay? Zukyun! I love you!
四六時中愛をちょーだい
Give me love 24/7
はて？
Huh?
いーいじゃん！　バキュン　愛愛愛なのな
It's fine! Bakyun! Love, love, love!
宇宙に１／２じゃもったいない
1/2 in the universe is just a waste
避けても結局見えないあいつの胸の内
Even if I avoid it, I can't see into that guy's heart
強がっても背伸びも気取りもいらないかな
Maybe I don't need to act tough, stretch myself, or put on airs
先輩後輩ヤンキージャンキー関係ない
Seniors, juniors, Yankees, junkies—it doesn't matter
いざ尋常に勝負
Now, let's have a fair fight
君ともしもその気なら
If you and I are both in the mood
ボニータが始まりそうならさ
If it seems like a bonita is about to start
まだ見ぬ技繰り出す
Unleash a technique yet unseen
僕らではそうさスウィートだな
For us, yeah, it's sweet
アレはどこか同じだね
That part of us is somehow the same
無茶苦茶で無茶苦茶な
Reckless and messy
修羅場派手にドラマが鳴るよ
The scene of carnage will ring out with drama
意味深な like you
Meaningful like you
曖昧な愛より三振
Better to strike out than have a vague love
四の五の言わず愛してちょうだい
Don't give me any excuses, just love me
待って1ミリな手中に鼻血ぶーなのだ
Wait, a 1mm gap leads to a nosebleed
自分の意思はどんなもんじゃい
How strong is your own will?
い、い、い、のずきゅん I love you なのだ
I-I-I Love You
四六時中愛をちょうだい
Give me love all the time
ほら、い、い、い、掴まきゅん愛、愛、愛、愛はろきゅう
Look, I-I-I caught you, L-L-L-Love Rocket
1/2がたまんない
Half of it is irresistible
恋なんて試練、愛したい試練
Love is a trial, wanting to love is a trial
毎晩一歩先輩たりないや
I'm one step short of my senior every night
不前絶後天真爛漫
Unprecedented and innocent
恋愛無常明鏡止水
Impermanence of love, a clear and serene mind
せーの、1、2、3、はい！
Ready, set, 1, 2, 3, go!
ハッハッハッハッハッハッハッハイヤ
Ha ha ha...
ハッハッハッハッハッハッウーサッサッサ
これよりご覧頂きますのは私共の栄枯盛衰...
What you are about to see is our rise and fall...
一見は勧善懲悪悪者共を一刀両断...
At first glance, it's about rewarding good and punishing evil, cutting down villains in one stroke...
ハッハッハッハッハッハッハッハイヤ...
Ha ha ha...
どこからともなく現れてすぐにどこかへ行っちゃう神出鬼没...
Appearing out of nowhere and disappearing just as quickly, elusive...
千変万化人の心は複雑怪奇...
Ever-changing, the human heart is complex and mysterious...
もうどうにも満身創痍あぁ巡り巡って夜の街
Already covered in wounds, oh, wandering around the night city
君は合図で踊り出すはぁ〜
You start dancing at the signal, haa~
回れ回れ回れ回れ回れ回れ回れ回れ回れ！華麗に花弁散らすように
Spin, spin... like scattered petals
回れ回れ回れ回れ回れ回れ回れ回れ回れ！髪も振り乱して
Spin, spin... even with disheveled hair
一昨日昨日今日と明日と明後日とこの宴は続く
The day before yesterday, yesterday, today, tomorrow, and the day after tomorrow, this banquet continues
踊れ歌え一心不乱に回れ今宵は雪月花
Dance, sing, spin with all your heart, tonight is the Snow Moon Flower
ハッハッハッハッハッハッハッハイヤ
Ha ha ha...
ハッハッハッハッハッハッハッハ
ねぇねぇこの世に平安訪れるの？...
Hey, will peace come to this world?...
濡れ衣を着せられて一攫千金...
Being framed, getting rich quick...
もう全く奇想天外あぁ辿り辿って夜の街
Simply bizarre, oh, arriving at the night city
迷い一つなく踊り出すはぁ〜
Start dancing without a single doubt, haa~
回れ回れ回れ回れ回れ回れ回れ回れ回れ！華麗に花弁散らすように
Spin, spin... like scattered petals
回れ回れ回れ回れ回れ回れ回れ回れ回れ！髪も振り乱して
Spin, spin... even with disheveled hair
一昨日昨日今日と明日と明後日とこの宴は続く
The day before yesterday, yesterday, today, tomorrow, and the day after tomorrow, this banquet continues
踊れ歌え一心不乱に回れ今宵は雪月花
Dance, sing, spin with all your heart, tonight is the Snow Moon Flower
花で一つ、
One with a flower,
鳥で二つ、
Two with a bird,
手打ち鳴らす
Clapping hands
風で三つ、
Three with the wind,
月出て四つ
Four as the moon appears
鳴らす鳴らす......
Ring it, ring it...
花で一つ、
One with a flower,
鳥で二つ、
Two with a bird,
手打ち鳴らす
Clapping hands
風で三つ、
Three with the wind,
月出て四つ
Four as the moon appears
鳴らす鳴らす......
Ring it, ring it...
今は
Now it is
回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ！
Spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin!
華麗に花弁 散らすように
Like petals scattering brilliantly
回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ！
Spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin!
髪も振り乱して
With hair all disheveled
一昨日、昨日、今日と、明日と、明後日と
The day before yesterday, yesterday, today, tomorrow, and the day after,
この宴は続く
This banquet continues
踊レ、歌エ、
Dance, sing,
一心不乱に回レ！
Spin with single-minded devotion!
今宵は何曜日？
What day is tonight?
水木金？
Wed, Thu, Fri?
土日月火？
Sat, Sun, Mon, Tue?
よー、ぽん！
Yo, pon!
らっしゃいな 平は成り
Welcome, peace is established
時が来た 正夢
The time has come, a dream comes true
夢現 夜もすがら
Between dream and reality, all night long
変わりゆくことに 恐れなし
No fear of changing things
のっぴきならぬのはごめん
Pardon me, I can't back out
手毬唄うたい
Singing a ball-bouncing song
君たちが誘う
You all invite me
やな重に後ろ髪を引かれても
Even if I'm reluctant to leave the deep mountains
進むべきなり
I must move forward
流行り廃うの浮世なら
If it's a transient world of fashion and decay
信ずる者はただ君だけと
The one I believe in is only you
踊り騒ぎや 飲み明かしや
With wild revelry and drinking all night
案ずることなどない この世
There's nothing to worry about in this world
人の世は恨めしい 銭はちゃらちゃら
The world of men is regrettable, money clinks
虚仮威しで混じり合え
Mingle with empty bluffs
それそれそれそれ！
Sore sore sore sore!
今を嘆いて昔を愛でても
Even if you lament the present and cherish the past
君の心の内 花の涙川
Within your heart, a river of flowery tears
それじゃ敵わん どこへも
That won't do, wherever you go
めくるめく舞台に君を連れて
I'll take you to the dazzling stage
あまうてなども悲しき
Even rain and such are sad
身勝手なのが世の理か
Is it the way of the world to be selfish?
万人待ちの理想 刻まないでよ
Don't carve out the ideals everyone waits for
刹那な応えなどは 徒ら
Fleeting answers are in vain
僕ら巡り逢うこと まさに一期一会
Our meeting is truly a once-in-a-lifetime encounter
酸いも甘いも知れぬ 試練連れ添って この手握って
Trials with unknown bitterness and sweetness, together with you, holding this hand
生きづらいこと浮世から
From this world where it's hard to live
旗を掲げよう 宵闇が明く
Let's raise the flag, the twilight clears into light
踊り上がりや 寝れば忘らら
Dancing and jumping, forget it all when you sleep
昔も今も変わらず 浮世
Past and present, the transient world remains unchanged
人の世は嘆かわしい いつだってちゃらちゃら
The world of men is lamentable, always clinking
可笑しさんで笑い合え
Laugh together at the absurdity
それそれそれそれ！
Sore sore sore sore!
深まる春も 凍てつく雪の日も
Both the deepening spring and the freezing snowy days
日出ずるすべての 瞬きと見よう
Let's view them all as fleeting moments of the rising sun
彩る色 どこまでも
Brilliant colors, stretching everywhere
曇りなき晴らしを 眺めて
Gazing at the cloudless landscape
明けて花一匁
Opening Hana-Ichimonme
欲しがる 欲しがる 欲しがる声
The voices wanting, wanting, wanting
勝って選んで 飽きないでいて
Win and choose, please don't get bored
猿真似の無礼千万 満ち足りないないない
Imitation is utterly rude, never satisfied
未だ進む道半ばだ
I'm still halfway through my path
如何なる時も歩を前へ出せ
No matter what, step forward
流行り廃うの浮世なら
If it's a transient world of fashion and decay
信ずる者はただ君だけと
The one I believe in is only you
踊り上がりや 飲み明かしや
With wild revelry and drinking all night
案ずることなどない この世
There's nothing to worry about in this world
人の世は恨めしい 銭はちゃらちゃら
The world of men is regrettable, money clinks
虚仮威しで混じり合え
Mingle with empty bluffs
それそれそれそれ！
Sore sore sore sore!
今を嘆いて昔を愛でても
Even if you lament the present and cherish the past
君の心の内 花の涙川
Within your heart, a river of flowery tears
それじゃ敵わん どこへも
That won't do, wherever you go
夢もめくるめく 終いはよいよい
Dazzling dreams too, the end is good.
君を連れて
Taking you with me.
余りてなどか 頻ぞかなしき
Why is it so lonely and overflowing?
身勝手なのが 世の理か
Is being selfish the way of the world?
移ろわばこそ 心などどをも
If things change, then even hearts and such...
忘るることなど あらざらむ
...will surely never be forgotten.
よぉーっ！
Yo!
じゅげむ じゅげむ 五劫のすりきれ
Jugemu, Jugemu, the sweep of five kalpas,
かいじゃりすいぎょの すいぎょうまつ うんらいまつ ふうらいまつ くうねるところに すむところ
Gravel and water-fish, mats of water-industry, mats of cloud-come, mats of wind-come, places to eat and sleep and places to live.
やぶらこうじの ぶらこうじ
Buried paths of yew trees,
ぱいぽ ぱいぽ ぱいぽの しゅーりんがん
Paipo, Paipo, Paipo's Shuuringan,
しゅーっ！
Shuu!
しゅーりんがんの ぐーりんだい
Shuuringan's Gurindai,
ぐーりんだいの ぽんぽこぴーの ぽんぽこなーの ちょうきゅうめいの ちょうすけ
Gurindai's Ponpokopii, Ponpokonaa, Chokyuumei's Chousuke!
ちょいとお時間いただきます
We'll take a bit of your time.
ご清聴ください
Please lend us your ears.
整いました！
It's all set!
笑うこととかけまして お祭り野郎と解きます
Comparing laughter with a festival enthusiast.
おや？
Oh?
そのこころは？ そのこころは？
And the answer is? And the answer is?
どちらもハッピー（法被）になるでしょう
Both will be happy (in a festival coat)!
おあとがよろしいようで
That's all for now.
笑おう 笑おう さあ笑いましょう こんな時代こそ 笑いましょう
Let's laugh, let's laugh, let's all laugh together. In times like these, let's laugh.
笑おう 泣いたら負けだ やけくそ笑いましょう
Let's laugh, if you cry you lose. Let's laugh with reckless abandon.
波乱万丈 すいもあまいも 乗り越えたあっぱれ日本人
Ups and downs, bitter and sweet. Admirable Japanese who overcame it all.
笑おう どんな時でも なにくそ笑いましょう
Let's laugh, no matter what happens. Let's laugh with a 'never give up' spirit.
ぐわっはっは にょほっほ
Gwahhaha! Nyohohho!
空気なんて読まずに笑っとけ
Don't bother reading the room, just laugh!
笑顔！ 笑顔！
Smile! Smile!
笑う門には福来たる！
Fortune comes to those who laugh!
えー 皆様 本日はようこそおいでいただきました
Ahem... Everyone, thank you for coming today.
ここで一席！
And now, a story!
ねずみの娘がお嫁に行って、じきに帰ってきたんでねずみのお母さんが、大変怒って
A mouse's daughter went to get married and came back soon after, so the mouse mother was very angry.
「あんな、いいところへ おまえ嫁いで
"You married into such a good family,
誰が嫌で 出てきたんだい？」
who did you dislike so much that you left?"
「いいえ、だーれも嫌じゃないんですけど、
"No, I didn't dislike anyone,
ご隠居さんがやさしいんで、嫌なの。」
but the old master was so kind, I hated it."
「優しいんなら結構じゃないかねぇ。」
"If he's kind, isn't that wonderful?"
「でも、猫なで声ですもの。」
"But he used a cat-like coaxing voice!"
忙しさに身を任せて
Leaving yourself to the busyness.
消えていくだなんて
To think things would just disappear.
べらんめえ！
Good heavens!
笑おう 笑おう 笑えなくても 笑うしかないでしょ 笑いましょう
Let's laugh, let's laugh. Even if you can't, there's nothing to do but laugh.
笑おう 口角上げて ひたすら笑いましょう
Let's laugh, raise the corners of your mouth. Just keep laughing.
鬼の乱 大飢饉さえ クリアして現代日本人
Onin War, Great Famine... modern Japanese who cleared them all.
笑おう 未来永劫 ぐははと笑いましょう
Let's laugh, forever and ever. Let's laugh with a 'guhaha'!
小娘のたわごとと切り捨てないで
Don't just brush it off as a young girl's nonsense.
しかめっつらなんか変な顔 笑顔を見たいから
A frown is such a strange face. Because I want to see your smile.
笑おう 笑おう さあ笑いましょう こんな時代こそ 笑いましょう
Let's laugh, let's laugh, let's all laugh together. In times like these, let's laugh.
笑おう 泣いたら負けだ やけくそ笑いましょう
Let's laugh, if you cry you lose. Let's laugh with reckless abandon.
波乱万丈 すいもあまいも 乗り越えたあっぱれ日本人
Ups and downs, bitter and sweet. Admirable Japanese who overcame it all.
笑おう どんな時でも なにくそ笑いましょう
Let's laugh, no matter what happens. Let's laugh with a 'never give up' spirit.
ひたすら笑いましょう
Just keep on laughing.
ぐわっはっは にょほっほ
Gwahhaha! Nyohohho!
空気なんて読まずに笑っとけ
Don't bother reading the room, just laugh!
笑顔！ 笑顔！
Smile! Smile!
笑う門には福来たる！
Fortune comes to those who laugh!
徒花ネクロマンシー
Adabana Necromancy
死んでも夢を叶えたい
I want to fulfill my dreams even if I die
いいえ、死んでも夢は叶えられる
No, dreams can be fulfilled even in death
それは絶望？それとも希望？
Is that despair? Or is it hope?
過酷な運命乗り越えて
Overcoming a harsh fate
脈がなくても突き進む
Even without a pulse, we push forward
それが私たちのサガだから
Because that's our Saga
誰が弔う
Who will mourn?
死地は彼方
The place of death is far away
静寂を破り
Breaking the silence
芽吹いた夢を
The dreams that sprouted
穿て
Pierce
重なる屍
The layered corpses
高みへ
To the heights
届くまで
Until it reaches
唸れ
Roar
徒花
Fruitless flowers
朽ち果てても進め
Even if we decay, move forward
奪わせはしない
I won't let it be taken
尊厳の愚弄に
To the mockery of dignity
牙を剥き放て
Show your fangs and release
枯れても走る
Even if withered, we run
此処を命と呼べ
Call this place life
空に叫ぶ
Cry out to the sky
脱・生存の定義
Defining survival
骨を斬らせて
Letting bones be cut
闇を断て
Sever the darkness
雲間に光る
Shining between the clouds
簒奪の勝機
The opportunity for usurpation
覚悟を
Preparedness
宿命に突きつけて
Thrusting it upon fate
天下に狂い咲く
Wildly blooming under the heavens
SAGA
傷ひとつ無い
Without a single scratch
手など愚か
Hands are foolish
意思も自由も
Both will and freedom
その身を投げ打て
Throw your body into it
守れ
Protect
退くな
Don't back down
涙も血も無い
No tears or blood
神話を
Mythology
築くまで
Until it's built
燃えろ
Burn
修羅花
Shurabana
鼓動なき世界で
In a world without heartbeats
摂理に抗い
Resisting providence
天命も無礼
Mandate of heaven is also rude
鎖断ち切って
Cut the chains
心を無くす
Losing heart
ことが死と知れ
Know that it is death
極めど儚い
Fleeting to the extreme
偶像の籠児
The caged child of idols
目には目を剥き
An eye for an eye
牙を剥け
Show your fangs
いつか誰もが
Someday everyone
散華する捨て石
Discarded stones that fall gracefully
輝け
Shine
刹那無限の火花
Endless sparks of a moment
乱世に逆らう
Resisting the turbulent times
SAGA
何が神の裁きか
What is God's judgment?
裁きなどさせない
I won't let there be judgment
希望高らかに
Hope loudly
打ち鳴らせ
Strike it out
呼吸よりも生きた証
The proof of living, more than breathing
唸れ
Roar
徒花
Fruitless flowers
朽ち果てても進め
Even if we decay, move forward
奪わせはしない
I won't let it be taken
尊厳の愚弄に
To the mockery of dignity
牙を剥き放て
Show your fangs and release
枯れても走る
Even if withered, we run
此処を命と呼べ
Call this place life
空に叫ぶ
Cry out to the sky
脱・生存の定義
Defining survival
骨を斬らせて
Letting bones be cut
闇を断て
Sever the darkness
雲間に光る
Shining between the clouds
簒奪の勝機
The opportunity for usurpation
覚悟を
Preparedness
宿命に突きつけて
Thrusting it upon fate
荒野を駆ける
Running through the wilderness
乱世に挑む
Challenging the turbulent times
天下に狂い咲く
Wildly blooming under the heavens
サガ
Saga
渡月橋 ～君 想ふ～
作詞：Mai Kuraki　作曲：Akihito Tokunaga
Togetsukyo ~Kimi Omou~
Lyrics: Mai Kuraki, Composition: Akihito Tokunaga
寄り添う二人に君がオーバーラップ
You overlap with the two of us close together
色なき風に思い馳せて
Letting my thoughts fly in the colorless wind
触れた手の温もり今も
The warmth of the hand I touched even now...
Stop 時間を止めて
Stop, please stop time
そういつの日だって
Yes, no matter what day it is
君の言葉忘れないの
I will not forget your words
会いたい時に会えない
I can't see you when I want to see you
切なくて もどかしい
It's painful and frustrating
から紅に染まる渡月橋
Togetsukyo bridge dyed in deep crimson
導かれる日願って
Wishing for the day I'm guided
川の流れに祈りを込めて
Putting a prayer into the river's flow
I've been thinking about you
いつも こころ 君のそば
Always, my heart is by your side
いにしえの景色変わりなく
The ancient scenery remains unchanged
今この瞳に映し出す
Reflected in these eyes now
彩りゆく季節越えて
Passing through the seasons that turn colorful
覚えてますか
Do you remember?
ねぇいつになったら
Hey, when will it be...
また巡り会えるのかな
...that we can meet again?
会いたい時に会えない
I can't see you when I want to see you
この胸を焦がすの
It burns my heart
から紅に水くくるとき
When the water is bound by deep crimson
君との想いつなげて
Connecting my feelings with you
川の流れに祈りを込めて
Putting a prayer into the river's flow
I've been thinking about you
いつも 君を探してる
I'm always searching for you
君となら不安さえ
With you, even anxiety...
どんな時も消えてゆくよ
...will disappear at any time
いつになったら優しく
When will I be able to...
抱きしめられるのかな
...be embraced gently?
から紅の紅葉達さえ
Even the crimson autumn leaves...
熱い思いを告げては
...tell of their passionate feelings
ゆらり揺れて歌っています
Gently swaying and singing
I've been thinking about you
いつも いつも 君想ふ
Always, always, I think of you
はい！というわけでここまではどうでしたでしょうか？
Yes! So, how did you like this part?
いや、もう数多くのゲストに出ていただいて、余は本当に嬉しいです！
Wow, I'm really happy that so many guests appeared!
本当に今回のライブは最初にも言ったんですけど、ちょっと和風な感じでまとめさせていただいたので。
As I said at the beginning, I put together this live concert with a Japanese-style theme.
曲ももうほぼほぼ全部和風っぽい感じで、
Almost all the songs were Japanese-style,
ちょっと雰囲気をね、一つに統一して今回はライブを作らせていただきました。
so I created this live by unifying the atmosphere into one.
そして、みんな気づいたかな？ちょっと歌ってる最中、ちょっと気づきました？これ。
And did everyone notice? Did you notice while I was singing? This.
お、気づきました？新しいマイクなんですよ！すごいでしょ？
Oh, did you notice? It's a new microphone! Isn't it amazing?
すごいでしょ？え、見て見て！この、ちょっとこの、わかりますか？
Amazing, right? Look, look! Can you see this?
このお腹の柄とちょっとお揃いなんですよ！
It matches the pattern on my stomach!
ちょっとこっちも、あ、見えるかな？見える？
This side too... can you see it? Can you?
ほら！え、めっちゃ可愛いでしょこれ！
Look! Isn't this super cute?!
イェーイ！これ新しいマイク、
Yay! This is my new mic,
あ、ここもね飾りも付いてるんですよ
and look, it has these decorations too,
この鈴とこの紐もね付いてて可愛いでしょ～
with these bells and this string, isn't it cute?!
イェーイ！これもね、お似合いです！
Yay! This also suits me perfectly!
やったー！
I did it!
はい！ということで、え、今回はですね、
Okay! So, for this time,
まだサプライズが残っております！
there are still some surprises left!
ですが、
However,
え、その前にちょっと告知をさせていただこうかなと思います！
before that, I'd like to make a few announcements!
それでは、告知、ドドン！
Now then, for the announcements, boom!
百鬼あやめ 活動7周年記念グッズ
Nakiri Ayame 7th Anniversary Memorial Goods
百鬼あやめ活動7周年記念グッズ！
Nakiri Ayame 7th Anniversary Memorial Goods!
イェーイ！
Yay!
はい、えーということで、
All right, so,
最初はこちら！
the first one is this!
卓上屏風
Desktop Screen
卓上屏風です！
It's a desktop screen!
めっちゃ可愛いでしょすごい！
It's super cute, isn't it?! Amazing!
デスクに立てて飾れるサイズの屏風となっております。
It's a screen of a size you can stand on your desk.
こちらはですね、我美蘭先生の描き下ろしの、
This is an illustration by Gabiran-sensei,
本日着ている新衣装と同じです！
and it's the same as the outfit I'm wearing today!
同じ屏風をね、ちょっと飾ってくださいねみんな。はい。
Please display this same screen, everyone. Yes.
え、可愛いでしょ。このね、ステージも背景のステージも
Isn't it cute? And both this stage and the background,
ちょっとそれっぽい感じに合わせていただきました。可愛い！
were made to match the vibe. So cute!
湯呑
Tea Cup
続いて、こちら！湯呑みとなっております！
Next up is this! It's a teacup!
こちらはですね、三川あゆむ先生に描き下ろしいただいた、
This is an illustration by Mikawa Ayumu-sensei,
ぽよよに乗っかったですね、
depicting me riding on a Poyoyo,
今回もこちらの新衣装で乗ったよがミニキャラで書かれた湯呑みとなっております。
a mini-character of me in this new outfit!
可愛いでしょ、こうやって乗ってます。乗ってます。
Cute, right? I'm riding it like this. Riding it.
はい。可愛いでしょ。
Yes. Isn't it cute?
扇子
Folding Fan
そして続いてはこちら！
And next up is this!
こちら扇子となっております！
It's a folding fan!
こちらもそうです！
This is the same!
新衣装と同じ柄の、え、扇子となっております。
It's a fan with the same pattern as the new outfit.
ちょっとね、ど真ん中に「余」って入ってるんですけど、
It has 'Yo' (I) right in the middle,
こちら入れるかすごい迷いました。
and I really debated whether to include it.
この余を入れるか入れようかな、どうしようかなと、
I wondered if I should include it or not,
運営さんとちょっと話し合ってこちらになりました。
and after talking it over with staff, this is what we got.
ちょっとね、あの、この余の右左で、
On either side of the 'Yo',
ちょっと新衣装っぽい感じにさせていただきました。
it's designed to give a feel like the new outfit.
卓上ライト
Desktop Light
そしてそして、続いてこちら！卓上ライトとなっております！
And then, next up is this! It's a desktop light!
行灯風の卓上ライトで、新衣装にこちらもですね
It's a lantern-style light, and like the others,
合わせた和風のデザインとなっております。
it's got a matching Japanese-style design.
ぜひね、飾って、和風っぽい風情あるお部屋タイムを
I'd love for you to display it and enjoy a Japanese atmosphere
過ごしていただきたいなということで、
in your room, so...
ちょっと和風寄りのライトにさせていただきました。
...we made the light with a Japanese feel.
可愛いでしょこれ。いいよね！
Isn't it cute? It's great, right!
めっちゃ考えました、こちらおすすめです。はい。
I thought about it a lot, so I highly recommend it.
ボイス
Voice
はい、続いてこちら！こちらですね、お馴染み販売ボイス。
Next up is this! The usual voice recordings.
こちらのタイトルは「新衣装でデート」ということで、
The title is 'Date in the New Outfit',
内容は新衣装の余と水辺で、え？
and the content is a date by the water with me. Wait...
水辺でデートしている内容となっております。
...a date by the water?!
メッセージにもね、ちょっと水辺を後ろにね、ありますけども。はい。
The message also has a waterfront in the background. Yes.
そしてそして、え、フルセット購入の方はこちらです！
And for those who buy the full set, here's the bonus!
数量限定バージョンは直筆サイン＆箔押し複製メッセージ入り、
The limited-quantity version has a handwritten signature,
我美蘭先生描き下ろしのポストカードとなっております。
plus a foil-stamped message on a Gabiran-sensei postcard.
通常バージョンはですね、箔押し複製サインとメッセージ入りの
The regular version comes with a foil-stamped signature
我美蘭先生描き下ろしポストカードとなっております。
and message on a postcard illustrated by Gabiran-sensei.
さらに、新衣装リスナーに褒めてもらって喜んでいる
Additionally, it includes a bonus voice of me
余の特典ボイスが付いてきますね。はい。
getting happy being complimented by all of you. Yes.
タイトル「またデートしようね」というボイスなんですけど、
The title is 'Let's go on a date again',
まあね、気になる方はぜひ聞いていただければと思います。
so if you're curious, please give it a listen.
まあ恥ずかしいのでここら辺にしときます。はい。
Well, it's embarrassing, so I'll stop there. Yes.
ということで以上、百鬼あやめ活動7周年記念グッズでした！
So, that's it for my 7th Anniversary Memorial Goods!
みんな買ってね、よろしくお願いします！
Please buy them, everyone! Thank you!
ということで、なんですが、こちら、まだ終わってません！
And with that said, we are not finished yet!
まだチャンネルはそのままにお願いします！
Please stay tuned to the channel!
ということで、まあね、最初ちょっと言った、
So, as I mentioned briefly at the start,
そろそろ、まあサプライズをね、みんな気になってると思うんで、
I'm sure you're all waiting for the surprise,
ちょっとサプライズにいっちゃおうかな～と思います！
so I think I'll get to that surprise now!
みんな気になるよね！気になる気になる～！
Everyone's curious, right?! You are, you are!
え、そうで～すよね！
Yes, I thought so!
とその前に、このステージ上へ参ります！
But before that, let's head up to this stage!
ぐんぐんぐんぐん、わ～！上上がってる！
Up, up, up we go! Wow! We're rising!
みんな見て、すごいでしょ。みんな見てる、見えてる、
Everyone look, isn't it amazing? Are you all watching?
みんな見て！ステージも夜も見て！
Everyone look! Look at the stage and the night view!
はい、ということで！
Alright then!
こちら上に上がってきたんですけれども、
I've come up here,
ま、上でね、何をやるのかと、
and, well, you might wonder what I'll do up here.
うすうすちょっと気づいてるんじゃないのかなとは思うんですけれども！
I think some of you might have an inkling, but still!
何かわかるかな？みんな。
Do you know what it is? Everyone.
教えて、教えて、教えて！
Tell me, tell me, tell me!
みんな何だと思う？何だと思う？
What do you think it is? What do you think?
お、何か... お、お、お餅？（笑）
Oh, something... Oh, mochi? (Laughs)
お、遊んでますねー、お、なんと！
Oh, you're just playing around. Well!
はい、こちら！なんとこちらです！ドドン！
Yes, here! It's this! Ta-da!
新曲『花吹雪』でーす！やったー！
It's my new song, "Hana Fubuki"! Yay!
いや、もうだいぶ長らくお待たせしたと思うんですけれども、
I think I've kept you waiting for quite a long time,
余のオリジナル曲の新しいのはいつだ？みたいな感じで待っていたかと思うんですけど、
wondering when my next original song would be out.
えー、こちら、作詞作曲Vellさんに書いていただきました！
This one was written and composed by Vell-san!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
テーマはですね、『可憐な歌声』×『和風ロック』！
The theme is "lovely vocals" x "Japanese-style rock"!
可愛いだけじゃない、一味違うオリジナルソングとなっております！
It's an original song that's not just cute, but something a bit different!
はい、この綺麗で可憐で、重厚な和風ロックとなっておりますので、
It's a beautiful, lovely, yet heavy Japanese-style rock song,
メロディとか歌詞もこだわり抜いて、磨き上げていただいた楽曲となっておりますので、
and since the melody and lyrics have been refined with great care,
ぜひぜひ、皆さん聴いてください！
everyone, please, please listen to it!
9月4日、本日の0時からですね、各種音楽サイトでリリースされるので、
It's being released on various music sites starting today, September 4th, at midnight,
ぜひ聴いてください！聴いてね！いっぱい聴いてね！
so please listen to it! Listen to it, okay? Listen to it a lot!
はい、それでは皆さん、大変長らくお待たせいたしました。
All right then, everyone, thank you so much for waiting.
最後はこの新曲『花吹雪』を送らせていただきたいと思います！
Lastly, I'd like to perform this new song, "Hana Fubuki"!
感想なども、この衣装もステージと一緒にポストしてください！たくさんポストしてねー！
Please post your impressions, along with the outfit and stage! Post a lot, okay!
最後にはメン限パートで、ちょっと衣装のお写真撮ったり詳しいお話もしたり、
And at the very end, in the members-only part, we'll take photos and talk in detail,
ミニライブもありますので、そちらの方もぜひぜひ見に来てくれたら嬉しいです！
and there's a mini-live too, so I'd be happy if you came to see that as well!
はい、それでは聴いてください。『花吹雪』！
All right then, please listen to it. "Hana Fubuki"!
共に散る　宿命なら
If it's our destiny to fall together,
派手に散りましょう
let us fall in style.
花吹雪
A flurry of falling petals.
ひらひら　舞い落ちる空
Fluttering down from the sky,
とうに散った　うたかたの夢
the ephemeral dreams that have long since fallen.
千の花は　麗しく咲く
A thousand flowers bloom beautifully,
叶う逢瀬は　刹那
a tryst fulfilled is but a fleeting moment.
艶やかに舞い
Dancing elegantly,
蝶の儚き命
the butterfly's short-lived life.
するり堕ちる　今宵は何処
Slipping away, where to tonight?
天つ風揺れ
The heavenly winds swaying.
狂おしく　今咲き誇れ
Bloom in full glory now, distractedly.
共に散る　宿命なら
If it's our destiny to fall together,
光満ちた　舞台で舞え
dance on the stage filled with light.
闇を裂く　旋律は
The melody that rends the darkness,
ゆらりと薫る
fragrantly wafts.
夢を咲かせましょう
Let us make our dreams bloom.
花吹雪
A flurry of falling petals.
くらくら　燃ゆるは焔
Dizzying, the burning flames,
遠く咲いた　明くる日の夢
the dream of the next day that bloomed afar.
正か否か　惑わずに往こう
Whether right or wrong, let's go without hesitation,
過去の痛みを胸に
with the pain of the past in our hearts.
誰そ彼に
In the twilight,
祈りをひとつ
a single prayer.
涙の川を
Upon the river of tears,
穿つ声響く
a piercing voice echoes.
慎ましく　ただ進むだけ
I will simply move forward, modestly.
茜さす　空の果て
At the edge of the madder-red sky,
褪せた過去の　憧れを見る
I see the faded yearnings of the past.
澄み渡る　静寂に
In the clear silence,
未来を繋ぐ
connect the future.
答え求むれど
Though I seek an answer,
術も無し
there is no way.
星の降る　夜明けまで
Until the dawn when stars fall,
続く歌よ　彼方へ届け
O continuing song, reach far away.
湧き上がる　情熱が
The welling passion,
世界を照らす
will illuminate the world.
共に散る　宿命なら
If it's our destiny to fall together,
光満ちた舞台で笑え
Smile on this stage filled with light
闇を裂く旋律は
This melody that tears through the darkness
ゆらりと薫る
Swaying and fragrant
夢を咲かせましょう 花吹雪
Let's make our dreams bloom, a storm of falling cherry blossoms
7周年！！ライブ見てくれてありがとう！！新衣装にキレイなステージどうだったかな！？
7th Anniversary!! Thank you for watching the live!! How did you like the new outfit and the beautiful stage!?
みんなが少しでも笑顔になってくれたら嬉しいです！！😊 8年目もよろしくね…！！！！！💕 余より
I'd be happy if I could make you smile even just a little bit!! 😊 Please keep supporting me in my 8th year...!!!!! Love, Yo